Marcel Breuer Papers
Marcel Breuer Papers
- Project Records, 1922-1982 (inclusive); 1940-1980 (bulk); 89 linear feet of manuscript material, 24,618 drawings, 6,160 photographs and slides.
  - DE BIJENKORF DEPARTMENT STORE COMPLEX, Rotterdam, Netherlands (1955-1957) [Commercial], (Alternate names: Parking Garage)
    - Photographs, 62
      - View Out from Entrance Hall [Slide 540], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Night View of Exterior Space Sculpture and Elevation [Slide 541], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Sign at Main Entrance [Slide 542], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Night View of Illuminated Sign at Main Entrance [Slide 543], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Night View of Elevation with Illuminated Sign/ Windows [Slide 544], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Construction Field Office from Above [Slide 545], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Main Entrance Doors with Custom Handles [Slide 546], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Entrance Vestibule [Slide 547], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Glass pavilion and Building Elevation [Slide 548], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Site Model with Context [Slide 549], model, model; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Illuminated Model Elevations at Corner [Slide 550], model, model; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Elevation [Slide 551], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Glass Pavilion under Construction [Slide 552], finished project, interior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Glass Pavilion under Construction [Slide 553], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Construction Progress on Glass Pavilion [Slide 598], finished project, exterior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View of Henry Moore Sculpture on Upper Level Terrace [Slide 512], finished project, exterior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - View Thorugh Staggered Windows [Slide 533], finished project, interior view; (color slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
  - DE BIJENKORF DEPARTMENT STORE PARKING GARAGE, Rotterdam, Netherlands (1970-1974) [Commercial]
    - Drawings, 38
      - Composite plan, elevation studies, area calculations., [Design Development Drawings]; 8; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - Scheme B (Nos. 1-3) 10 Apr 1970; Scheme C (Nos. 1-5) 10 Apr 1970; Scheme D (1 unnumbered) 7 Aug 1970., [Design Development Drawings]; 9; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - 14 Sep 1970 (Nos. 1-6). Plans, Elevations, Sections., [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - Feb - Mar 1971 and Revisions May 1972. Plans, Elevations, Sections, Details., [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - 25 Feb 1972 (Nos. 5-9, 6A). Elevations., [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - Elevations (undated)., [Presentation Drawings]; 2; (originals) (Tube 1121)
      - 17 Aug 1972. Rendering. Elevation., [Presentation Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1121)
  - DE FRANCESCO APARTMENT, Berlin, Germany (1929) [Interior]
    - Drawings, 10
      - Ablegeplatten im Vorraum (Nr. 410) [Leaf 341a] (10 Feb 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Ahorn Natur Mattiert (Nr. 409) [Leaf 340a] (5 Feb 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Tisch (Nr. 401) [Leaf 332a] (26 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 3)
      - Bettwand (Nr. 398) [Leaf 329] (25 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 4)
      - Bücherwand (Nr. 400) [Leaf 331a] (26 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 9)
      - Schrankwand (Nr. 397) [Leaf 328a] (25 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 9)
      - Bettbügel (Nr. 411) [Leaf 342a] (20 Feb 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 25)
      - Grundriss Rudolstätterstr. 9 (Nr. 395) [Leaf 326a] (24 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 25)
      - Schreibtisch (Nr. 396) [Leaf 327a] (24 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Oversize 25)
      - Schrankwand Wohnz (Nr. 399) [Leaf 330a] (26 Jan 1931), [Working Drawing ] [German]; 1; (originals) (Map-case 75)
    - Published Material
      - Bedroom and study-living-dining room, (magazine clippings ) (Oversize 19, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 7
      - Bedroom Wall Cabinets., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 11)
      - Study/Living Room., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 11)
      - Bedroom., finished project, interior view; (black and white photographs) 1 (Box 119, Folder 11)
      - Bedroom and study-living-dining room. [Slide 735], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Study/Living Room. [Slide 680], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Bedroom. [Slide 346 ], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
      - Bedroom Wall Cabinets (two views). [Slide 237], finished project, interior view; (black and white slides) 1 (Box SL-2)
  - DE GUNZBURG CHALETS, Megève, France (1964) (not built) [Residential, Single]
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence: Architects (1964), Robert Gatje (Box 128, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence: Client (1963-1964), Baron Alain de Gunzburg (Box 128, Folder 9)
      - Miscellaneous (1963), Advisory in French from Construction ministry; business card from French architect (Box 128, Folder 10)
  - DEFENSE HOUSING, Wethersfield, CT (1942) (not built) [Residential, Multi], (Alternate names: Wethersfield Project)
    - Project Files
      - Correspondence: Client, FWA/NHA (Box 85, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Contractors/Manufacturers (Box 85, Folder 2)
      - Office Records, rough sketches, preliminary cost estimates, office correspondence, receipts and site sketch (Box 85, Folder 3)
      - Specifications, government issued standards/specifications for defense housing (Box 85, Folder 4)
  - DEPARTMENT OF HEALTH, EDUCATION AND WELFARE (HEW), HEADQUARTERS (HUBER H. HUMPHREY FEDERAL BUILDING), Washington, DC (1972-1976) [Government], (Alternate names: HEW (DHHS)/FOB/South Portal)
    - Drawings, 330
      - Partial Tentative Sketches [30 Apr 1968]: Architectural (21-1 to 21-12), Structural (21-13 to 21-23), [Working Drawings]; 23; (originals) (Tube 1221)
      - Tentative Sketches [c. 1969] (Sverdrup and Parvel): Structural (21-201 to 21-216), [Working Drawings]; 16; (reproductions) (Tube 1222)
      - Tentative Sketches [29 May 1969] (Joseph R. Loring and Associates): Mechanical-Electrical (21-301 to 21-313), [Working Drawings]; 13; (reproductions) (Tube 1222)
      - Tentative Sketches [29 May 1969] (Joseph R. Loring and associates): Mechanical-Electrical (21-401 to 21-410, 21-500 to 21-515), [Working Drawings]; 26; (reproductions) (Tube 1223)
      - Completed Tentative Sketches [29 May 1969]: Dwg. Nos. 21-101 to 21-141, incomplete, [Working Drawings]; 36; (reproductions) (Tube 1224)
      - Tentative Sketches [c. 1969]: Lighting (E509 to E515), [Working Drawings]; 7; (reproductions) (Tube 1224)
      - Construction Set [31 Aug 1970] ("final revision, 1 Oct 1970") (most annotated): Architectural (5-1 to 5-62, with some duplicates), [Working Drawings]; 65; (originals) (Tube 1225)
      - Executive Conference Room: Audiovisual Projection Plan (Dwg. No. 509-1) [12 Apr 1974], [Working Drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1226)
      - HEW Executive Areas [18 Oct 1974]: Dwg. Nos. CD-1 and CD-5, [Working Drawings]; 2; (hybrids) (Tube 1226)
      - Conference Room and Interior Details [9 Dec 1969-31 Aug 1970]: Architectural (5-38 to 5-59 incomplete and unnumbered sheets, [Working Drawings]; 17; (mixed) (Tube 1226)
      - Executive Suites and Conference Room [10 Feb 1975]: Architectural (11-A-1 to 11-A-11, with some duplicates), [Working Drawings]; 12; (originals) (Tube 1226)
      - Federal Office Building at the South Portal Site: Diagrammatic Study [20 Feb 1968]: Situation Plan (20-1), Street Level Floor Plan (20-2), Mezzanine Floor Plan (20-3), Typical Office Floor Plan (20-4), Penthouse Floor Plan (20-5), Sections (20-6), Elevations (20-7), 1st Basement Floor Plan (20-8), 2nd Basement Floor Plan (20-9), 3rd Basement Floor Plan (20-10), [Presentation Drawings]; 10; (originals) (Tube 1227)
      - Master sheets for "Diagrammatic Study" presentation set, [Presentation Drawings]; 10; (originals) (Tube 1227)
      - Misc. master sheets, [Presentation Drawings]; 7; (mixed) (Tube 1227)
      - Film negatives for "Diagrammatic Study" presentation set, [Presentation Drawings]; 10; (reproductions) (Tube 1228)
      - Diagrammatic Study presentation set (small format, on plastic sheets), [Presentation Drawings]; 11; (reproductions) (Tube 1228)
      - Diagrammatic Study presentation set (small format, sepia diazo prints), [Presentation Drawings]; 10; (reproductions) (Tube 1228)
      - Rendering: Street Level View (by Pierre Lutz) [photostat], [Presentation drawings]; 1; (reproductions) (Tube 1228)
      - Construction Set [31 Aug 1970] ("final revision, 1 Oct 1970"): Cover Sheet (0-1), Site Survey (1-1), Test Boring (1-2 to 1-4), Planting Plan (17-1), Site (2-1 to 2-8), Floor Plans (3-1 to 3-23), Elevations and Sections (4-1 to 4-3), Food Service (5-KE1 to 5-KE11) [45] [originals] [8] [prints], [Working Drawings]; 53; (mixed) (Tube 1435)
    - Project Files
      - Acoustical Design (Dec 1972-Dec 1975) (Box 194, Folder 1)
      - Art Work (Nov 1974-Jan 1977) (Box 194, Folder 2)
      - Bid Documents I (Feb 1972), Bid summaries and abstracts (Box 194, Folder 3)
      - Bid Documents II (Aug 1966-Nov 1973), Cost estimates and bid analysis (Box 194, Folder 4)
      - Change Requests I (Jun 1973-Dec 1975) (Box 194, Folder 5)
      - Change Requests II (Jan 1976-Sep 1976) (Box 194, Folder 6)
      - Concrete Specifications (Jun 1967), Architectural and Structural Concrete (Box 194, Folder 7)
      - Contract Amendments (Jan 1969-May 1976), Amendments Nos. 1-14 (Box 194, Folder 8)
      - Contract Amendments (Aug 1971-Oct 1975), Proposals (Box 194, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence: Blake Construction (Apr 1972-May 1974) (Box 195, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Blake Construction (Jun 1974-Mar 1977) (Box 195, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jun 1967-Dec 1968) (Box 195, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jan 1969-Dec 1969) (Box 195, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jan 1970-Dec 1973) (Box 195, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jan 1974-Jun 1974) (Box 195, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jul 1974-Dec 1974) (Box 196, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: GSA (Jan 1975-Dec 1976) (Box 196, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Joseph R. Loring (Jan 1968-Oct 1976) (Box 196, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Nov 1967-Nov 1968) (Box 196, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1969-Dec 1969) (Box 196, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1970-Dec 1970) (Box 196, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1971-Jul 1971) (Box 197, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Aug 1971-Dec 1971) (Box 197, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1972-Dec 1972) (Box 197, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1973-Jun 1973) (Box 197, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jul 1973-Dec 1973) (Box 197, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1974-Dec 1974) (Box 197, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence: Nolen-Swinburne (Jan 1975-Jan 1977) (Box 197, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence: Sverdrup and Parcel (Dec 1967-Jun 1977) (Box 198, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence: Various Suppliers, Consultants and Service Providers (Jan 1968-Dec 1969) (Box 198, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence: Various Suppliers, Consultants and Service Providers (Jan 1970-Nov 1970) (Box 198, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence: Various Suppliers, Consultants and Service Providers (Mar 1971-Feb 1976) (Box 198, Folder 4)
      - Diagrammatic Study (20 Feb 1968) (Box 198, Folder 5)
      - Graphics and Signage I (Nov 1970-Mar 1972), Page, Arbitrio and Rosen (Box 198, Folder 6)
      - Graphics and Signage II (Sep 1975-Feb 1977), RTKL (Box 198, Folder 7)
      - Graphics and Signage I (Jun 1978-Jun 1979), GSA (Box 198, Folder 8)
      - Interiors: Executive Areas I (May 1975-Sep 1976), General Correspondence (Box 199, Folder 1)
      - Interiors: Executive Areas II (Jan 1975-Apr 1975), Construction Cost Estimates (Box 199, Folder 2)
      - Interiors: General Correspondence (Jul 1974-Dec 1976) (Box 199, Folder 3)
      - Interiors: Specifications for Painting and Finishing (Apr 1968) (Box 199, Folder 4)
      - Interiors: Specifications for Partitions (Box 199, Folder 5)
      - Lighting (Dec 1968) (Box 199, Folder 6)
      - Litigation I: Correspondence (Mar 1979-Sep 1980) (Box 199, Folder 7)
      - Litigation II: Correspondence (Feb 1981-Jul 1981; May 1984-Jun 1984) (Box 199, Folder 8)
      - Litigation III: Deposition of Herbert Beckhard (15 Oct 1976) (Box 199, Folder 9)
      - Memoranda (Sep 1971-Jan 1977) (Box 199, Folder 10)
      - Office Records: Bicentennial Exhibit (Apr 1975-Sep 1976) (Box 200, Folder 1)
      - Office Records: Correspondence with Photographer (Apr 1973-Dec 1976) (Box 200, Folder 2)
      - Office Records: Misc. Correspondence and Clippings (Dec 1968-Apr 1980) (Box 200, Folder 3)
      - Office Records: Misc. Notes (Apr 1976) (Box 200, Folder 4)
      - Office Records: Occupancy Calculations (Box 200, Folder 5)
      - Plaza Improvements I (Oct 1978-Feb 1979) (Box 200, Folder 6)
      - Plaza Improvements II (Mar 1978-Jan 1981) (Box 200, Folder 7)
      - Possible Revision to Health Suite (Box 200, Folder 8)
      - Slate (Nov 1969-Jan 1972), Exterior slate and paving (Box 200, Folder 9)
      - Surveys and Test Boring (Oct 1968-Oct 1970) (Box 200, Folder 10)
      - Transmittals I (Jul 1971-Nov 1974) (Box 200, Folder 11)
      - Transmittals II (Dec 1974-Aug 1976) (Box 200, Folder 12)
      - Transmittals III (Jul 1974-Jun 1975), Interiors (Box 200, Folder 13)
    - Published Material
    - Photographs, 153
      - Steel work (17 contact sheets) (13 xerox copies), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 30 (Box 201, Folder 1)
      - Steel work (17 contact sheets) (13 xerox copies), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 22 (Box 201, Folder 2)
      - Construction Progess Photos (Jun 1972), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 5 (Box 201, Folder 3)
      - Construction Progess Photos (Oct 1973-Nov 1973), construction, exterior view; (negatives) 10 (Box 201, Folder 4)
      - Construction Progess Photos (Jul 1972-Mar 1973), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 32 (Box 201, Folder 5)
      - Construction Progess Photos (Apr 1973-Sep 1973), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 24 (Box 201, Folder 6)
      - Construction Progess Photos (Oct 1973-Nov 1974), construction, exterior view; (black and white photographs) 30 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - DEPARTMENT OF HOUSING AND URBAN DEVELOPMENT (HUD), HEADQUARTERS, Washington, DC (1965-1968) [Government], (Alternate names: HHFA (HUD)/Robert C. Weaver Federal Building)
    - Drawings, 1785
      - Perspective rendering (Helmut Jacoby, 1964) [graphite on tracing paper, mounted on illustration board, 29.75 x 40 in.], [Design Development Drawings]; 1; (mixed) (Map-case 119, Folder 6)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Sprinklers (9-SP-1 to 9-Sp-3), AC (9-AC-1 to 9-AC-55)., [Working Drawings]; 58; (reproductions) (Tube 192)
      - Preliminary plans and studies [Aug-Sep 1963] (some with pencil annotations)., [Design Development Drawings]; 30; (mixed) (Tube 193)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Plumbing (9-P-1 to 9-P-31)., [Working Drawings]; 31; (reproductions) (Tube 193)
      - Preliminary plans and studies [Aug-Oct 1963] (some with pencil annotations): includes core designs, Modular and Dimensional Investigations (SC1-9), Corner Elevations., [Design Development Drawings]; 38; (mixed) (Tube 194)
      - Exterior façade details/variations and Wall Module Studies (transparencies and drawings) [Nov 1963]., [Design Development Drawings]; 73; (mixed) (Tube 195)
      - Schematic plans, area calculations, core study and cost comparisons., [Design Development Drawings]; 11; (mixed) (Tube 195)
      - Reflected ceiling/lighting sketches., [Design Development Drawings]; 7; (originals) (Tube 195)
      - Office floor plans., [Design Development Drawings]; 7; (mixed) (Tube 195)
      - Preliminary schemes: Site, Plans and Elevations [photostats]., [Presentation Drawings]; 6; (reproductions) (Tube 195)
      - "GSA Marked Up Tentative Architectural Drawings" [4 Aug 1964]: Nos. 21-1 to 21-28 and 72 (line rendering)., [Working Drawings]; 29; (reproductions) (Tube 196)
      - "Tentative Sketches, Structural and Mechanical Drawings. Set for Marcel Breuer and Associates" [4 Aug 1964]: Nos. 21-29 to 21-37, 21-40 to 21-71., [Working Drawings]; 41; (reproductions) (Tube 197)
      - GSA Set [13 Oct 1964] ("25% Submission Set"): Nos. 7-1 to 7-5, 7-9 to 7-16, 7-18 to 7-19, 7-26 to 7-28., [Working Drawings]; 18; (reproductions) (Tube 198)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set"): Nos. 7-9 to 7-28, 7-30 to 7-31., [Working Drawings]; 24; (reproductions) (Tube 198)
      - "Sent to NSA" [5 Feb 1965]: misc. details., [Working Drawings]; 14; (reproductions) (Tube 198)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set") [with pencil annotations]: Nos. 0-1, 2-1, 3-1 to 3-14, 4-2 to 4-3, 5-1, 5-3, 5-4, 5-6, 5-7, 5-12 to 5-20, 5-23 to 5-27, 5-29 to 5-35, 5-37, 5-40 to 5-44, 5-46 to 5-49, 5-51 to 5-52, 5-55, 5-57, 5-58, 5-70, 5-74, 5-75., [Working Drawings]; 62; (reproductions) (Tube 199)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set'): Nos. 0-1, 17-1, 1-6, 2-1, 3-1 to 3-14, 4-1 to 4-3, 5-1, 5-3, 5-4, 5-8 to 5-20, 5-23 to 5-27, 5-29 to 5-31, 5-36 to 5-44, 5-51, 5-52, 5-55, 5-58, 5-70, 5-75., [Working Drawings]; 61; (originals) (Tube 200)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 0-1, 2-1, 3-1 to 3-14, 4-1 to 4-3, 5-1 to 5-20., [Working Drawings]; 39; (reproductions) (Tube 201)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 5-21 to 5-74, 7-1 to 7-4, 17-1., [Working Drawings]; 59; (reproductions) (Tube 202)
      - GSA Set [13 Oct 1964] ("25% Submission Set") [w/pencil annotations]: Nos. 0-1 (Index to Drawings), 1-0 to 1-5 (Surveys), 2-1 (Site Plan), 3-1 to 3-14 (Floor Plans), 4-1 to 4-3 (Elevations), 5-1 (Architectural), 5-8 to 5-15, 5-17 to 5-20, 5-23 to 5-27, 5-29 to 5-32, 5-36, 5-38 to 5-42, 5-49 to 5-51, 5-60, 5-61, GSA Standard Details., [Working Drawings]; 71; (reproductions) (Tube 203)
      - Various plans and details: includes kitchen/food service details and mail room elevator (5-29) [some w/pencil annotations]., [Working Drawings]; 14; (reproductions) (Tube 204)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set"): Nos. 5-61 to 5-66 (Kitchen/Food Service)., [Working Drawings]; 6; (reproductions) (Tube 204)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 5-16 to 5-63, 5-65 to 5-68 (Kitchen/Food Service), 7-9 to 7-28, 7-30 to 7-35, 9-AC-22, 9-AC-24, 9-AC-26., [Working Drawings]; 37; (reproductions) (Tube 204)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Nos. 0-1, 17-1, 1-0 to 1-6, 2-1, 3-1 to 3-14, 4-1 to 4-3, 5-1 to 5-21., [Working Drawings]; 48; (reproductions) (Tube 205)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Nos. 5-22 to 5-74, 7-1 to 7-4., [Working Drawings]; 57; (reproductions) (Tube 206)
      - Progress Prints and distribution copies [c. Oct 1964][some w/pencil annotations]: includes entrance plaza/lobby, admin. Suite, conference rooms, site grading, kitchen/food service, end wall finishes and screen wall., [Working Drawings]; 29; (reproductions) (Tube 207)
      - Electrical process drawings [Jun-Aug 1964][w/annotations]: includes interior/exterior lighting plans and details, and "Live Load Delineation" (Paul Weidlinger)(LD-1 to LD-3)., [Working Drawings]; 41; (reproductions) (Tube 208)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Nos. 7-5 to 7-37., [Working Drawings]; 33; (reproductions) (Tube 209)
      - GSA Set [18 Feb 1965]: Nos. 9-E-1 to 9-E-56., [Working Drawings]; 56; (reproductions) (Tube 210)
      - Details, revisions, consultant drawings and distribution copies (c. Oct-Dec 1964)[some w/pencil annotations]: includes paving/landscaping, elevators, space plan, admin. Suite details, conference rooms, end wall revisions., [Working Drawings]; 51; (reproductions) (Tube 211)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-E-1 to 9-E-55., [Working Drawings]; 55; (reproductions) (Tube 234)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-SP-1 to 9-SP-3 (Sprinklers), 9-P-1 to 9-P-15, 9-P-19 to 9-P-22, 9-P-25 to 9-P-28., [Working Drawings]; 26; (reproductions) (Tube 235)
      - GSA Set [7 Jan 1965] ("75% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-AC-1 to 9-AC-29, 9-AC-31, 9-AC-33 to 9-AC-40, 9-AC-43 to 9-AC-45, 9-AC-47 to 9-AC-53, 9-AC-55., [Working Drawings]; 49; (reproductions) (Tube 236)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-AC-1 to 9-AC-20, 9-AC-22 to 9-AC-45., [Working Drawings]; 44; (reproductions) (Tube 237)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-P-1 to 9-P-19, 9-P-21 to 9-P-22., [Working Drawings]; 21; (reproductions) (Tube 238)
      - GSA Set [24 Nov 1964] ("50% Submission Set"): Nos. 9-E-1 to 9-E-6, 9-E-8 to 9-E-38, 9-E-40 to 9-E-43, 9-E-44 to 9-E-51., [Working Drawings]; 48; (reproductions) (Tube 239)
      - GSA Set [1 Apr 1965]: Nos. 0-1, 1-0 to 1-5, 2-1, 3-1 to 3-14, 4-1 to 4-3, 5-1 to 5-40., [Working Drawings]; 65; (reproductions) (Tube 1101)
      - GSA Set [1 Apr 1965]: Nos. 5-41 to 5-74, 7-1 to 7-4, 11-100 to 11-105 (Contract Change Drawings, Mar-Dec1966), 11-201 to 11-210 (Contract Change Drawings, Dec 1966 - Jan 1967), 17-1, 34-1 to 34-2 (Granite Facing Alternate "L", May 1965)., [Working Drawings]; 57; (reproductions) (Tube 1102)
      - Office Set [Jun 1964] ("Tentative Sketches") [w/pencil annotations]: 21-1 to 21-33, S-1 to S-8 (plumbing, HVAC, site plan)., [Design Development Drawings]; 73; (reproductions) (Tube 1103)
      - Office Set [4 Aug 1964] ("Tentative Sketches"): 21-1 to 21-30 (site plan, floor plans, elevations, sections)., [Design Development Drawings]; 30; (originals) (Tube 1104)
      - Various plans and details [Jan 1963-Jan 1964][w/ annotations]: includes site work (surveys, topo surveys, test boring reports), Diagrammatic Sketches (20-1A to 20-7A), square footage computations, floor plan work., [Design Development Drawings]; 51; (mixed) (Tube 1105)
      - Various plans and details ("Tentative Drawings. Development of Visual Details - Int/Ext, elevations)[Jun 1964-Feb 1965][w/ annotations]: includes interior/exterior details, structural details (pour joints), Dimensional/Modular Studies (geometrical form of building), Tree Columns, basement and garage plans., [Design Development Drawings]; 65; (mixed) (Tube 1106)
      - Presentation Set [17 Jun 1964]: Nos. 1-7 (site plan, floor plans, elevations, transverse sections), presentation labels., [Presentation Drawings]; 13; (reproductions) (Tube 1107)
      - Line renderings (3 elevations - 1 marked "Record")., [Presentation Drawings]; 3; (reproductions) (Tube 1107)